欢迎来到机器人视觉课程的最后一个讲座，感谢您的光临。
Welcome to the last lecture in the Robotic Vision course and thanks for hanging in there.
我们已经谈了很多关于图像形成方式，我们如何改变三维图像的方法
We've talked a lot about the way that images are formed, how we transform the three-dimensional
世界变成了二维图像。所有这一切都有一个潜在的假设
world into a two dimensional image. And an underlying assumption in all of that has been
相机静止不动，物体静止不动。
that the camera is stationary and the object is stationary.
那么现在我们要考虑相机移动的情况。第一件事
Well now we're going to consider the case where the camera is moving. The first thing
我们要看一下当相机在太空中移动时图像是如何变化的。
we're going to look at then is how does the image change as the camera moves through space.
然后我们将翻转并说，让我们说我有一些东西的形象
And then we're going to flip it around and say, let's say that I've got an image of something
在图像中看起来像这样，我希望它在图像中看起来像这样。我们是什么
that looks like this in the image and I want it to look like this in the image. What we're
试图解决的是相机应该如何移动才能改变图像
going to try to work out is how should the camera move in order to change the image from
对此。
this to this.
相机必须改变它的视角，所以我们想直接解决相机的问题
The camera has to change its viewpoint and so we want to work out directly how the camera
应该移动，以实现这一目标。这是一种称为“基于视觉的控制”的技术
should move in order to make that happen. This is a technique called "Vision Based Control"
有时被称为“视觉伺服”，这是我花了很多钱的主题
sometimes called "Visual Servoing" and is a topic that I've spent a good deal of my
生活在思考。
life thinking about.